This is Detective Jack Mosley. Shield number 22 7.
我是探员Jack Mosley 徽号227
I guess this will be my last will and testament.
这将是我的遗嘱和最后的誓词
This is for Diane.
这是写给Diane的
When this day is over, they're gonna come and talk to you about this...
当一切结束时,他们将会与你谈这事...
...and they're gonna-- They're gonna tell you what happened, Diane.
他们将会... 他们将会告诉你发生的一切,Diane...
But what they tell you is not really what happened here.
但是他们说的,并不是事实
So I hope that you get this.
所以我希望你能拿到这份遗书
I was trying to do a good thing.
我一直在尽力把事情做好
Police! Get down! Everybody, down!
警察!下来 所有人,都下来
Down! Get down!
下来!都下来
Go, go, go! Come on!
快!快!过来
-Clear. -Police. Get down.
-没有人 -警察,快下来
Deal it off.
处理一下
Agent 1 0-1 0, we're all secure.
代号 10-10,我们都安全
All right, we're out of here.
好的,全部离开
lt's clear.
没什么了
You smell that?
你闻到了?
Couple hours. We gotta move now. Would you turn that thing off?
几个小时了,我们得离开这儿, 你能把那个关上吗
All right, who's downstairs we don't need?
好的,楼下有没有闲人?
lt's all yours. Good luck.
全是你的了,祝你好运!
l hate to do this, Jack, but l need you to sit on this until uniforms get here.
我讨厌做这事,Jack, 坐在那儿,直到有人来接手
-All right. -Just hang until you're relieved.
-好的 -待在这儿,直到有人来接替你
All right.
好的
Don't touch anything.
不要动任何东西
Any word on the suspects?
嫌疑人都说些什么?
-What do you want me to tell you? -What did you tell them?
-你想让我说什么? -你跟他们说了什么?
l saw someone out there.
我看到有人从那儿出去了
Yeah, yeah. Come on.
好,好,继续往下说
-Anything for me? -Breath mints.
-有我的东西吗? -用来闻的薄荷
Sergeant Cannova called. Wants you to write up this wire request.
Dergeant Cannova来电话, 想让你记下来这个电报上的要求
Said to make sure you get the right dates on them.
要你确定和他们联系的日期
The particulars are on your desk, and he needs it by tonight.
详细说明放在你的桌上了, 他晚上要
All right.
好的
All right, well, we can have an officer come by about 8 a.m. tomorrow.
好的,明天早上8点, 我们有个长官要来
You gave her two?
你给了她两个?
Well, you know, we do what we can.
你知道,我们只能做些份内的事
Hey, Jack, l forgot to tell you, the lieutenant's looking for you.
嗨,Jack,我忘了告诉你, 助理在找你
He wants you to find him right away.
他让你立刻过去
Yeah, yeah.
好的
Well, listen. All right, well, l'll call you.
好的,听着 好的,我会再给你打电话的
Hey, Mosley.
嗨,Mosley
-Mosley. -Yeah.
-Mosley -嗯
Grace tell you to find me?
Grace告诉你过来找我了吗?
-Yeah, just a minute ago. -All right, need a favor.
-是的,刚才 -好的,来帮个忙
Get this guy from lockup and run him to Centre Dtreet.
把这个人从拘留所提出来, 带他到中心大街
The DA needs him ADAP. He's gotta be in front of a grand jury before 1 0.
DA需要他的证词, 他要在10点钟陪审团结束听审之前到那里
l signed out.
我已登记外出了
You signed the sheet?
你填表了?
Well, not technically, no. But l mean, l'm signed out.
没那么正式, 但是我的意思是说,我外出
Then consider yourself on overtime.
那你可以算加班
Captain Gruber called. We need this thing done.
Gruber上尉来电话了, 我们得把这事办了
Don't you got some mutt that takes care of this?
你没有其他的人可以做这事儿吗?
l got Keenan, but he's still on the Verrazano. He's behind some overturned truck.
Keenan,不过他还在亚利桑纳, 他塞车了
l'm tired. l mean, look, normally, you know me, l don't say no.
我很累了,我的意思是说, 你看看我,你知道我不愿做事的人
l know you been working all night, Jack...
我知道你已经干了一整夜了,Jack...
...but who's the detective and who's the lieutenant here?
但是在这儿, 谁是探员,谁是助理?
l mean, Jack, l got nobody else.
我的意思是说, Jack,我没有其他人选了
lt's a nothing thing.
这个算不上什么工作
One hundred and eighteen minutes to get a little hemorrhoid 1 6 blocks.
只有3个小时,仅仅16个街区
l'll let you come in to work late tomorrow.
明天早上,你可以晚点儿来上班
Yeah, yeah.
好吧
Edward Bunker.
Edward Bunker
Yeah, that's me, officer. Eddie Bunker, right here.
是我,长官 Eddie Bunker,在这儿
Down here, the last cell.
到这儿来,最后一间
-Come back in an hour. -What do you mean, come back?
-1个小时后回来 -回来?你指什么?
He's supposed to wear a suit when he leaves.
他离开时,应该穿身西装
-And? -lt's not here yet.
-那么? -那西装不在这儿
Just get him out here, all right?
带他走,好吗?
They said he'd wear a suit.
他们说他得穿套西装
No, yeah, l'm supposed to get a suit. lt's a three-piece suit. lt's gray.
不,噢,我还得弄套西装 三件套,灰色的
lt's got-- Wait. Yeah.
它...,等一下
lt's a three-button, it's gray, it's got cuffs on the pants.
三个扣子,灰色的,裤脚卷边
They brought the catalog down. l picked it out of the catalog.
他们写在表里了,我把它删掉
l'm not supposed to leave without it. Wait.
我不可以不穿它走,等等
l'm not supposed to leave without that suit.
我离开时,必须穿那套西装
-You tell it to him. -No, that's why you brought my shoelaces.
-你跟他说 -不,那就是为什么你要拿走我的鞋带
-Come on, come on. -l'm not supposed to.
-快点儿 -.我不认为是对的
-Yo, yo, you take the old lady, right? -Yeah, you sure?
-你带走了那个老太太,是不是? -嗯,你确定?
The old lady goes into the car, otherwise she dies.
那个老太太上了那辆车, 否则她会死的
-You think so? -Yeah, man.
-你这么认为? -是的
That's what-- l don't know. You gotta figure out the answer for yourself.
我不知道,你得自己找答案
Everybody just calm down. Officer, l'm going to court.
每个人都很冷静, 长官,我要去法院
-l'm supposed to have a suit. -Hey.
-我得穿那套西装 -嗨
Shut up. Here's your property.
闭嘴,这是你所有的东西
-lt's not a good sign. -Hands behind your back.
-这可不是个好兆头 -把手背到后面
-Hold on, l'm trying--
-等等,我要...
l don't even have my-- All my prop-- Wait one minute.
我甚至还没有拿到我的... 我所有的东...等一下
lt's not right. They promised me the suit.
这不对,他们答应给我一套西装的
l picked it out of the catalog-- Wait, my book.
-我把它从表里删掉了, -等等,我的书
l can't leave without my book. My book is very important to me.
没书,我就不走,这书对我很重要
Why are we rushing like this? lt's not a good sign.
我们干嘛这么着急? 这不是个好兆头
-Hey. -What's the damn answer?
-嗨 -那个该死的答案到底是什么?
-Hey! -Shut up.
-闭嘴
-l hate police. -Half a tank.
-我讨厌警察了 -一半警察
You could have had a little more patience.
你得有点儿耐性
This suit don't mean nothing to you. You probably got a bunch of suits.
这套西装对你意味着很多, 你可能会拿到好几套
But it's a whole different thing to me.
但是它对我来说却是完全不同的
These cars don't ever change, huh?
这些车从来就没变过
Traditional cruisers.
巡逻车还是老样子
And the same retarded hump in the middle.
中间还是那样
Smell the same way, like Lysol and vomit.
闻起来还是那个味道, 像来苏儿,让人想吐
l hope nobody vomited back here. They probably did.
我希望没人在这儿吐过 他们可能吐过
Hey, man, let me ask you something.
嗨,我想问你个问题
l'm trying to figure this out.
我一直想知道...
You driving along in your hurricane, right?
你在暴风雨中驾车,明白?
There's three people at the bus stop.
公共汽车站上有三个人
Yeah, one is an old lady. Dhe's sick, she about to die.
一个是老太太 她病了,要死了
The second one is your best friend.
第二个是你的好朋友
He saved your life, right?
他救了你的命,知道吗?
And the third is the girl of your dreams.
第三个,则是你的梦中情人
right, but check it out...
好好想想...
...you only got space in the car for one person.
你的车里只有一个位子
right? Who you take?
懂吗?你会载上谁?
lt's a riddle that's supposed to tell what type of person you are...
这是个谜语,能反映你... 你是哪种类型...
...like where you at in your life.
...就象在你的生活中
lt's a hypothetical question, man, damn.
这是个假设性的问题
lt's just a hypothetical--
只是假设...
Well, good. Fine, good. l guess that's my answer.
噢,好的,很好 我想那是我的答案
Why don't you get on the loudspeaker?
为什么不用你的扩音器?
Put the Hawaii Five-O light on or something.
打开警灯或者其他什么
Use your police power. Put on a little siren.
用一下你警察的权力, 鸣几下警笛
Make room, make a hole.
让开,让一下
lsn't that the saying, ''Make a hole, make a hole''?
不是这么说 "让开,让开"?
Go on, make a hole.
继续,让一下
Digns. Everywhere, signs, signs, signs. All over, man.
四处都在暗示,完蛋了
l used to not even see nothing like that, man.
我在之前常常什么都看不到
And then l start seeing them. And l start looking for them.
然后,我开始看到了, 我开始寻找
And everything just start falling in place.
所有的东西开始掉到你面前
l'm gonna be all right, where l'm supposed to be.
我会好的, 我想会好的
l ain't got my suit, but once they get my testimony...
我没拿到我的西装, 但是一旦他们有了我这个证据...
...they drop my charges, l'm free.
他们就放弃指控,我就自由了
lt's making sense to me.
这对我很有意义
l believe in that.
我坚信这一点
Being in the right place.
一切都走上了正轨
Being where you supposed to be. You believe in that?
一切都象你所想象的那样, 你不这么认为吗?
l believe life's too long and guys like you make it even longer.
我认为生命太漫长了, 尤其是对象你这样的人,显得更加漫长
Life's too long?
生命太漫长了?
Damn.
该死
That's some cold shit, man. l ain't never heard nobody say no shit like that.
这话有点儿冷吧, 我从来没听人他妈的这么说
Usually you hear about people trying to make their life longer, you know?
通常你会听到人们在努力去 使自己活得更长些,你知道吗?
Trying to stay alive a little longer. You sound a little...
尽量活得长一点儿, 你听起来有点...
...depressed or something, you all right?
...抑郁或者是别的什么,你还好吧?
You stopping?
你不开了?
This ain't the courthouse, man. What you doing?
这里不是法院 你要做什么?
Yo.
你
Yo, why you stopping?
你,为什么停下来?
You gonna rush me out to court, and now you stopping? What are you--?
你得送我去法院, 而你现在停车了?你是...?
Hey. Hey, man.
嗨,你
Hey, man. Listen, man, l got an important appointment after my court date, man.
嗨,你听着,我出庭后, 还有一个重要的约会
That shit ain't funny, man. Come on, man. lt's not a game, man.
那不是他妈的开玩笑, 快点儿,我们不是在做游戏
Yo.
你
Dome bullshit, man.
我不胡说了
Hey. Hey!
嗨,嗨
No, man. lt ain't Miller Time, man.
不,现在不是Miller时间
The weather will be clear early morning, but the rest of the day....
早晨天气很晴朗, 而全天其他的时段...
Dam. Hey, Angela.
嗨,Angela
So we are looking at a hot, humid day.
所以我们将看到炎热而潮湿的一天
Looks like temperature might reach 1 OO degrees...
温度可能会达到100度...
...so don't forget to pack your sunscreen.
...所以不要忘了带上你的防晒用品
Add a pack of these, will you?
那一套东西,不是吗?
l know this dude smelled funny. l got the wrong dude, man.
我知道这个人看起来还好, 我遇错人了
1 7.50. What?
17.5美元,啊?
Hey, don't open it. Come over here.
嗨,别打开,拿过来
What time is it, man?
几点了?
lt's 8:1 1 .
8:11
That's a good sign. That's a good sign.
那是好兆头,好兆头
l'm on my way. l'm gonna get there.
我正在路上,我就要到那儿了
-Want change? -No, you keep the change.
-找零吗? -不用,你留着吧
Keep the change. All right, you have a good day.
你留着那零钱吧 好的,祝你今天愉快
-l don't want the peanuts. -Bye.
-我不想要花生 -再见
No, man. Can't do nothing for you, understand?
不,帮不了你,看见了?
Hey, you better give me that change. l'm gonna need that.
嗨,你最好还是把那零钱给我, 我有些用处
You see my situation right here?
你看到我的情况了?
No, no, no! No, no, no!
不,不
Hey!
嗨
How am l supposed to get out?
我怎么出去啊?
-Come on. -Help me. Help me.
-快点 -帮帮我
-My book. Why did you stop? -Go, left, go. Left.
-我的书,为什么停车? -快跑,往左
Move. Move. Move.
快,快
Wait. Freeze!
等等,停
ln here. Come on.
这儿,快点
Dhit.
该死
Hey!
嗨
Just get out of here, now! Go on. Go!
离开这儿,现在 快,快
Come on, let's go. That way, let's go. Go, go.
快点,我们走 那边,走,走
ready? Here.
这儿
Let's go. Go.
走
-Dominic, get people out of here, right now. -Jesus, Jackie. What's going on?
-Dominic,让这儿的人都离开,立刻 -天啊,Jackie,发生了什么事?
-Everybody. You too. -All right, okay.
-所有人,包括你 -好的
-Let's go. -Come on, come on, come on.
-我们走 -快点
Hey, yo.
嗨,你
Come on, keep going. Come on. Come on, move it.
快点,快走 快点,离开
Yeah, this is Detective Jack Mosley, shield number 227.
是的,我是探员Jack Mosley 徽号 227
l am 1 0-1 3, at-- Hold on a minute.
我是1 0-1 3,等一下
-Dominic, what's the address here? -1 33 Mulberry.
-Dominic,这里的地址? -133 Mulberry
1 33 Mulberry.
133 Mulberry
Mulberry Dtreet.
Mulberry 大街
All right.
好了
ls they coming?
他们要过来了?
l don't know why you stopped, man.
我不明白你为什么停下来
l don't know why you would do that, man.
我不懂你为什么那么做
They said you were nobody.
他们说你无足轻重
-l ain't nobody. -Shut up.
-我很重要 -闭嘴
You a wino. You need to stop drinking, that's what you need.
你这个酒鬼,你停车去喝酒 那就是你需要的
Shut up.
闭嘴
Jack?
Jack?
-Frank. -Hey.
-Frank -嗨
You all right?
你还好吧?
-Yeah. -Yeah?
-是的 -嗯?
We were on Mott when the call went out. Heard it was you.
听到消息时,我们在Mott大街上 听到是你
Got here as soon as we could.
我们就尽快赶来了
Oh, hi.
噢,嗨
-Hey. -You all right?
-嗨 -你怎么样?
-Yeah, l'm all right. -You having fun?
-我挺好的 -好玩吗?
-No. -No? Oh, well.
-不 -不?很好
Gotta have fun.
好好玩
-What's up, Jack? -Hey, man. Hi.
-发生了什么,Jack? -嗨
You did a really great, great job, man.
你做的非常好
You got yourself a bad guy.
你现在状态很差
Been a while, huh? Yeah.
歇会儿?
We got the second shooter half a block from here, so it's done.
我们在距离这里半街区的地方听到 第二声枪响,所以一切都结束了
-Dure you're okay? -Yeah.
-你确定没事吗? -是的
l'm just getting my wind. l was running.
我只是在转弯,我在跑
Why don't you let us take it from here.
为什么不考虑让我们带走他?
Oh, yeah.
噢,是的
We'll get the kid where he belongs, and you don't have to worry about a thing.
我们送他去目的地, 你不必担心
-We'll get you home. -Yes, please.
-我们会把你送回家 -是的,求求你
Please, please, officer. That's a very good idea...
求求你,求你了,长官 这主意不错...
...because, honestly, l don't think this dude is doing too good.
...因为,坦白地说,我认为 这位先生做得不怎么样
l told him not to stop.
我告诉他别停车
l asked him not to stop. He just had to stop.
我央求他别停, 他还是停下来
That's when everything happened. Dude came to the window.
就在事发当时, 那个人来到窗口
l have a very important appointment aft--
我有个非常重要的约会,在...
Jack.
Jack
Hey, Dhue.
嗨,Shue
Come on. Here.
赶快,这儿
Why don't you take this. Come on.
为什么不带上这个?快点
We'll get you out of here. Got a car waiting. All right?
我们得离开这儿, 外面有车在等着呢,好吧?
Get some sleep.
睡会儿觉
Jack?
Jack?
The kid was gonna testify against Jerry.
这家伙的证词将对Jerry不利
He saw Jerry doing some business.
他看到Jerry在做一些事情
Now, we both know that Jerry has never been a standup guy like you and me.
我们都知道Jerry不像你我, 他是个靠不住的人
He'll roll over, they indict him. We can't have that.
他会倒打一耙,他们起诉了他 我们不能输
No. lt's gonna hurt a lot of us.
那将会牵连我们许多人
Come on.
快点
Dee, this whole thing caught us-- lt caught us completely unaware.
整个事情把我们... 把我们都蒙在鼓里
lt was supposed to be Teach's nephew driving him.
应当让Teach的侄子送他
But he got stuck out there in traffic, who knows where...
但是他塞车了, 天知道他在...
...so then your lieutenant, he pegged you.
...所以你们中尉,找到了你
You know, just the wrong time and the wrong place for you today.
你知道,今天对你来说, 只是错误的时间,错误的地点
All right. Now, you know that l would never put you in a position like this, right?
好的,现在,你知道 我不想让你陷入这样的困境,嗯?
You know that, huh?
你是知道的
And l never figured you'd cap one of those guys.
我从未想过你会去保护这样的人
-That's what l get for hiring drug addicts. -Grab the gun.
-那就是我为什么要向这个药瘾子开枪 -抓住这枪
Grab the gun. There you go.
抓住这枪,那边
Come on. Frank?
快点,Frank?
-Here we go. -All right, here we go. Jack.
-我们走 -好的,我们走,Jack
Dqueeze the trigger.
扣动扳机
All right. Let go of the gun. Let go of the gun.
好的,扔了这枪 扔下这枪
l figure it like this.
我说的就是这个
You.... You pop the guys trying to spring the kid.
你...你打死这些人 是为了嫁祸给这个家伙
The kid, well, he gets your gun.
这家伙,他拿了你的枪
And he takes you hostage.
他拿你做人质
Do we came in and saved the day.
我们进来了,救了你
He died, you lived.
他死了,你得救了
Now, this could be a good thing for you, Jack.
现在,这对你来说是件好事,Jack
Get you back where you belong.
回到你的住所
-Are you still with...? -Dtand up.
-你仍然和...? -站起来
-You still with what's-her-name? -Come on, stand up.
-你仍然和...,她的名字? -快点,站起来
-What are you waiting for? -What's her name?
-你在等什么? -她叫什么?
Caroline.
Caroline
lt's Caroline.
是Caroline
This changes everything, Jack.
这样做会使一切都发生改变
Over here.
过去
Come on, Frank.
快点,Frank
Kid, get up. Come on.
你,起来,快点
Dhit. Man, shit.
该死
All right, Jack, it's 8:25.
好的,Jack,现在是8:25
-You stay there. -Listen to me, the jury's tenure ends at 1 0.
-你呆在那儿 -听我说,陪审团听审的时间将在10点钟结束
All right? The kid gets there one minute past, all this...
行吗?这家伙到那儿, 过一会儿,所有这些...
...it doesn't matter.
...都将烟消云散
And all you gotta do is look the other way.
你要做的,就是从另一角度去考虑一下
All right? We still got options here.
行不行? 我们还可以选择
Okay?
行吗?
We just want the kid.
我们只想要这个人
Jack, Jack, Jack, just let me help you.
Jack,Jack,Jack, 让我帮帮你
All right?
好吧?
Back up.
向后退
Jack, once you go out that door...
Jack,一旦你出了那个门...
...l can't help you.
...我就帮不了你了...
Please just back up, Frank. Just back up.
请往后退,往后退
He shot a cop.
他打伤了一个警察
What the hell did you see? What did you see?
你到底看到什么了? 你看见什么了?
That cop back there.
那个警察
l seen him around my way...
我看见他在我附近...
...holding a gun in this little Puerto rican kid's mouth.
...拿着一把枪, 放到这个小波多黎各人的嘴里
Come on. Let's go.
快点,我们走
He said he'd kill his mother if he testified.
他说,如果他敢作证, 他就杀了他妈
What you doing that for? We need that.
你在做什么? 我们需要那个
The shell in that gun was over 20 years old. Lucky it went off at all.
那枪里的子弹已经超过20年了, 幸好它刚才还能响
-They didn't tell you Dhue was a cop? -No, they didn't tell me.
-他们没告诉你那个人是个警察? -没有,他们没说
They showed me a picture, that was it.
他们给了我一张照片,就这些
Well, congratulations, because you're about to testify against one of New York's worst.
噢,恭喜!你就要通过作证 来惩治纽约最坏的警察
-What? -Fellas, look, the clock's ticking.
-什么? -Fellas,看,时间在走
He's gotta be at the courthouse by 1 0. We know where he's going.
他会在10点钟到达那个法院, 我们知道他的路线
Mulvey, you're coming with me.
你跟我来
-Know where you're going? -Take the north side.
-知道你怎么走吗? -向北
-You got it, let's go. -Come on.
-知道了,我们走 -快点
-Captain. -Where are we, Frank?
-上尉 -我们在哪儿,Frank?
Well, we're putting descriptions out over precinct channels.
好吧,我们把巡逻区的街道仔细查一下
No names, or that one's a cop. lt'll help to have some eyes.
没有名字,或者说只有一个警察 这将有助于找到他们
-How long can you sit on this? -He shot a cop.
-你插手这事多久了? -他枪击了一名警察
You're the precinct captain, Dan. How long?
你是这个区的上尉,Dan 多长时间?
l don't know. Hour, maybe a little more.
我不知道 一个小时,也许更长些
-Who's on this with you? -My guys.
-谁和你一起调查? -我的手下
Ortiz and Maldonado from the 66. Touhey and Kaller from the 1 1 1 .
Ortiz和Maldonado来自66区 Touhey和Kaller来自111区
A couple others you don't wanna know about.
还有其他的人， 你应当不想知道
The guy was your partner for 20 years.
他是你20年的搭档
What the hell happened in there?
在那儿到底发生了什么?
-ls he drunk? -l don't know.
-他喝多了? -我不知道
l don't know. We woke him up.
我不知道,我们把他叫醒了
Hopefully he'll do what he always does, and we can go back to work.
希望他能依惯例行事, 我们就可以回去工作了
lf he doesn't?
如果他没有?
We gotta quash this thing before he gets his legs back.
我们得压住这事, 在他回来之前
These are his streets.
这里是他的地盘
This could get ugly for all of us if that kid talks.
事情对我们来说会很糟糕, 如果他开口的话
-He can't talk. -He won't talk.
-他不能说 -他不会说的
Look, l appreciate what you did for me back there...
看,我很感谢你在那儿 为我所做的...
...but l'm starting to think you're not the dude for this.
...我开始想... 你不是那样的
l mean, you're out of breath, you're hung-over.
我的意思是说, 你喘不过气,而且酒醉未醒
Your leg is gonna give out on you any second, man.
腿也走不动了
l got someplace l need to be at 1 2, you understand?
我得在12点到另一个地方, 你明白吗?
l need to be finished at court by 1 0...
我需要在10点钟结束法院里的事...
...or l'm not gonna get where l'm supposed to get.
...或者说我将到达不了我想去的地方了...
-You understand what l'm saying? -All right, l understand.
-你明白我在说什么吗? -是的,我明白
-You're not listening to what l'm saying. -Wait, come here. Come here.
-你根本没在听我说话 -等等,到这儿来
Come on.
快点
Hung-over.
酒醉未醒
A bad leg.
步履蹒跚
No gun.
身上没枪
-Bobby? -Yeah?
-Bobby? -什么事?
-You thinking what I'm thinking? -l'm already there.
-你明白我的意思吗? -我已经到那儿了
Oh, God.
噢,上帝啊
Come on, let's go.
快点,进来
Listen, just stay put right here. l'll be right back.
听着,呆在这儿 我这就回来
Come on, man, don't take long. We gotta go.
快点,别太久了 我们得赶快走
Hurry up.
快一点
-Hey, man, where your bathroom? -What?
-嗨,你的洗手间在哪儿? -什么?
Your bathroom. Where your bathroom at?
洗手间,你家洗手间在哪儿?
Down at the end of the hall.
客厅尽头
Yeah.
噢
That's what you look like when you smile, huh?
看你笑的样子
You was probably drinking then too.
你那时就已经喝了不少了
There's the lady.
还有个女士
redhead. She cute. That ain't bad.
红头发,很漂亮,不错嘛
Hey, man. Come on, don't be stopping to get high or nothing like that.
嗨,快点,别停下来
Man, we gotta go.
我们得走了
Make sure you lift the seat up before you go.
用马桶之前, 把马桶垫立起来
lt's up already.
它是立着的
Maybe you left it like that, huh?
也许你离开之前弄的
l'm coming.
我这就来了
Hey, Jack.
嗨,Jack
Jack Mosley.
Jack Mosley
Why did you do that?
为什么那么做?
Do what?
做什么?
Dhoot that cop.
向那个警察开枪
Cops...
警察...
...they don't shoot other cops.
...他们不会向其他的警察开枪
Especially over nobody like me.
尤其是为了象我这样一个无足轻重的人
lt's a long way to go for a stranger, you know.
对于一个陌生人来说, 还有很长的一段路要走,你是知道的
Thank you.
谢谢你
l never had nobody....
我从未有过什么人...
Hell, man, you know.
你知道
l don't rock with the police, you know what l'm saying?
我从来不和警察合作, 你明白我的意思吗?
-Finger off the trigger. -They never been my friend.
-把手离开扳机 -他们从来都不是我的朋友
-Then here you come. -On the ground.
-而你来了 -根本上
lt's kind of bugging me out, you know.
你改变了我的看法
You on some vigilante business.
你在做义警做的事
Let's go.
我们走
-Jack-- -Put your arms around the pole.
-Jack-- -用手抱着柱子
l don't know what to think anymore.
我不再知道你的想法了
-Here. Cuff yourself. -What are you doing, Jack?
-这儿,自己铐起来 -你想做什么,Jack?
Yeah, it's a little strange.
是有点奇怪
You know? By any definition, this here.
你知道吗?从任何角度去定义...
All right, kid. Good.
很好
Okay.
好的
Okay, okay, okay.
好
You should have done what you always do, Jack.
你总是依惯例行事,Jack
-Where's your phone? -lt's on the left-hand side.
-你的电话在哪儿? -左手口袋里
They know l'm here. lf l don't answer it....
他们知道我在这儿, 如果我不回话...
-Jack? -Let's go, kid. Come on.
-Jack?Jack? -我们走,快点
-Bob. -Bob's a little tied up right now, Frank.
-Bob -Bob现在有点麻烦,Frank
All right, I'm impressed, Jack.
好吧,我知道了,Jack
Did you shoot him too?
你也向他开枪了?
Dend someone to check on Bobby.
派个人去看看Booby
Jack, you're not up to this.
Jack,你管不了这事
All right? It's gonna end bad for you.
知道吗?只能是坏你的事
You lost the kid, didn't you?
你找不到那个家伙了,不是吗?
He bailed on you. Well, you know what?
他被你"保释"了,你知道吗?
That is the best thing that could have happened.
那将是最好不过的事了
So why don't you go home.
所以为什么不回到家里去
Forget about what happened.
忘记发生的一切
We'll take it from here. Are you looking for him?
我们会带他走的, 你在找他吗?
And you can't find him.
你找不到他
We're gonna find him, all right?
我们会找到他的,知道吗?
We're gonna find him.
我们会找到他
All right, Jack, now you can hang up.
好的,Jack,你现在可以挂电话了
Where are you, kid?
你在哪儿?
All right. Now, let's see which way he went.
好吧,现在我们瞧瞧, 他会走哪条路
Did he go up? Did he go down?
他是往前走,还是回去?
ln or out, Jackie. Which way did he go?
进,还是退,Jackie 他会选择哪一个?
Let's see if he went down.
如果他回去,就让我们来看看吧
-Excuse me, sir, do you mind swiping? -Get a job, man.
-打扰了先生,帮我刷下卡,行吗? -帮个忙
Ma'am, would you mind swiping me in?
夫人,帮我刷下卡吧
Ma'am? Ma'am, would you mind swiping me in, please, ma'am?
夫人,帮帮我,刷一下吧,求你了
l have a very important appointment l have to....
我有个重要的约会,我必须...
Excuse me, ma'am, would you mind--? Domebody mind swiping me in?
打扰一下,夫人,你愿意...? 有人愿意帮我刷下卡吗?
l'm trying to get to an important appointment.
我要去赴个重要的约会
Domebody help me. Domebody help me.
谁帮帮我,谁来帮帮我
Domebody help me.
来个人帮帮我吧
Hey.
嗨
Come here.
到这儿来
-Come on. Go. -Thank you. Thank you very much.
-快点,过去 -谢谢您,真是太太谢谢您了
Eddie!
Eddie
-Oh, no. -What are you doing?
-噢,不 -你在做什么?
-Why are you running? -What do you want?
-为什么要跑? -你想干什么?
lt's too much, man. l'm doing the rest on my own.
够了,我在做自己的事
l'm doing what l said. l'm getting out of here.
我在做我说过的事, 我要离开这儿
-lf l can find you, they can find you! -l'm doing what l said.
-如果我能找到你,他们也能 -我在做我说过的事情
Eddie, listen to me. Listen to me. Listen to me!
Eddie,听我说,听我说
-l'm your only friend down here. -No, you're not my friend.
-我现在只是你的朋友 -不,你不是我的朋友
-l can do this-- -Friend? You don't even know me!
-我能这么做... -朋友?你根本就不认识我
And get me where? You gonna get me shot.
想把我带哪儿去? 你可以向我开枪
Ever since l've been with you, people been trying to shoot me. People you know!
只要和你在一起, 他们就会杀了我,你是知道他们的
Look, man, l got someplace l need to be. l got something l need to do.
看,我要去我应该去的另一个地方 我要做我想做的事
Unless you gonna shoot me or arrest me, l'm going, Jack.
除非你杀了我,或者把我抓起来 我要走了,Jack
-l can't let you leave. -Thank you, Jack Mosley. l'm going.
-我不能让你走 -谢谢你,Jack Mosley,我要走了
-You can't leave. -Yes, l can. Thank you, Jack Mosley.
-你不能走 -是的,我能.谢谢你,Jack Mosley
Dtop. Don't do that. Dtop.
停下,不要那样,停下
Ladies and gentlemen--! You're not going. Come here.
女士们,先生们... 你走不了,到这儿来
Eddie!
Eddie
Okay, okay. Okay, we gotta go.
好 我们走
-Move! Move! -Get out of the way!
-闪开,闪开 -全都闪开
Move! Move!
躲开,躲开
-Here, come on. -What are you doing?
-这里,快点 -你在做什么?
Taxi! Hey!
出租车,嗨
Taxi!
出租车
lt's Kaller. He just missed them at the Canal Dtreet station.
我是kaller,他在Canal街地铁站, 刚刚让他们给跑了
Where, where, where?
哪儿,哪儿?
Dhit. Where the hell is he?
他究竟在哪儿?
Goddamn it.
该死
We're gonna find you.
我们会找到你的
Yeah, this is Detective Nugent. l need a triangulation...
是的,我是Nugent探员, 我需要跟踪...
...on Detective Torres' cell phone. Area code (91 7 ) 935....
...探员Toores的手机, 区号（917）935....
That cop back at the apartment, he said you should do what you always do.
那个在你公寓的警察, 他说你该按惯例行事
What did he--? What did he mean by that?
他说...? 他指的是什么?
You're not doing what you always do, huh?
你没在按惯例行事?
Jack Mosley, l get it. l see the signs.
Jack Mosley,我知道了,我看明白了,我看到了天意
l'm where l'm supposed to be. l was wrong. You're the right guy.
我得去我该去的地方 我错了,你是个合格的警察
l could have got another guy, did something different, but l got you.
我本来是应当另一个送的, 但是,却不料是你
l appreciate it. You're the right guy.
我很感激你,你是个好人
-Okay? -Okay.
-好了吗? -好了
-This is Comtech, over. -Yeah, go, this is Nugent.
-这是Comtech,结束 -是的,我是Nugent
GPD indicates they're on Bowery.
GPD显示他们在Bowery
Repeat, Bowery, moving south towards Pell.
重复,Bowery 往南,Pell方向移动
Speed indicates they're on foot.
速度显示,他们是在走
Are you hearing this, boys? He's in Chinatown.
听见了吗? 他在中国城
Let's move in.
我们去那儿
-What's the deal with that book? -lt's my business plans.
-那本书是怎么回事? -那是我的商业计划
l'm moving to Deattle. My sister's already living out there.
我要搬到西雅图去, 我妹妹住在那儿附近
l'm gonna open up a bakery. But it's only, like, a specialty bakery.
我要开一个面包店, 只是一种面包专卖店
Birthday cakes for little kids. There's a lot of money in that.
专门卖小孩子的生日蛋糕, 可以赚很多钱
l'm gonna send you a big birthday cake on your birthday--
我会送你一个很大的生日蛋糕, 在你生日那天
-l hate birthday cakes. -You hate birthday cakes?
-我讨厌生日蛋糕 -你讨厌生日蛋糕?
First thing that doesn't go your way...
刚开始,总不会那么顺利...
...you're gonna be slipping into Carol's Clip and Curl...
...你可以溜进Carolr的理发店...
...and stealing all her hair-care products.
...偷走她所有的护发用品
Because you're a thief. And that's what you are, Eddie.
那是因为你是个贼, 你就是那么个人,Eddie
-You're always gonna be a thief. -People can change, Jack.
-你总是个贼的样子 -人总会变的,Jack
-Days change, seasons change. Not people. -Yes, you do--
-日子在变,季节在变,可人不会变 -可是,你会变...
-People don't change, Eddie. -Yes, you do. l'll get you that cake.
-人是不会变的,Eddie -可你会变,我要送你那个蛋糕
You know what it's gonna say on top?
你觉得上面应当写些什么?
''Jack Mosley, ha-ha-ha, eat this.'' Make you eat your words, lick your fingers too.
"Jack Mosley,哈哈,吃下这个" 吃下你的话,舔舔你的手指
Dubject's moving west on Pell.
他们在向Pell的西面移动
Dubject now moving south on Doyers. Dtill moving south on Doyers.
他们在向Doyers的南面移动, 仍然在Doyers的南面
Bobby, you take Doyer, we got Pell. And, Kaller, you close up Bowery.
Bobby,你去Doyer,我们去Pell Kaller,你向Bowery靠近
-Copy that. -Let's squeeze him.
-就这么做 -堵住他
-Copy that, on my way. -Why don't you pull up. Pull up.
-按我刚才说的做 -你为什么停下来
-Dorry. -Who is that? You can't go in here.
-抱歉 -你们是谁?你们不能进去
Oh, sorry.
噢,抱歉,
Look, man, l gotta be down there. All right, you understand?
看,我得去那儿,你懂吗?
l gotta be down there that way, and there's streets and shit in between there.
我得到下边那条路去, 距离那里还有许多条街道
You got some sort of plan? Dome sort of police plan or something?
你有什么计划了吗? 一些警察的计划或是其他?
l see your limp acting up. You ought to get that checked out.
我看你的腿已经开始瘸了, 你得去检查一下
l have a buddy of mine walking around with a limp just like that.
我有个伙伴就象你那样走路
He don't wanna go to the doctor, though, right?
他不愿意去看医生,尽管如此,知道吗?
Finally he go, they say it's a fracture, right?
最后,他去了, 他们说是骨折,明白?
And now it's infected. They gotta cut it off at the knee.
已经感染, 要从膝盖以下锯掉
Wasn't so bad, though. He had no more pain.
尽管如此,可没那么糟 他不再感到疼痛了
He ended up moving to Jersey, working for the PATH...
他不再迁往新泽西了, 在路上走...
...being a motorman. Got a pension and shit now.
...坐着轮椅 拿着退休金,一直到现在
l guess everything happens for a reason, you know what l mean?
我想任何事情能够发生都是有原因的, 你明白我的意思吗?
You're a sunny little shit, l'll give you that much.
你还有美好的未来, 我会给你的
Get in here! Get in that door!
进去!进那个门!
Jack!
Jack
-Pull me in! Help me in! -Come on, come on, come on.
-拉我一把,拉我进去 -快点,快点
Lock the door.
锁上门
-Wait, wait, wait. -Hold up.
-等等,等等 -举起来
Come on.
快点
-You all right? -Yeah.
-你还好吗? -嗯
Jack, what are we doing? Where are we going?
我们在做什么? 我们要去哪儿?
-Come on. -Where we going, Jack?
-快点 -我们去哪儿,Jack?
Out of the way.
离开这儿
Over here.
过来
Jack? How we even know that Centre Dtreet Courthouse is in this direction, Jack?
法院是在这个方向,Jack?
Jack? We gotta know--
Jack?我们得知道...
Down! Head down!
爬下,把头低下
Go!
快
Come on!
快点
Kaller!
Kaller
Push it.
拉开门
You all right, Jack?
你还好吗,Jack?
l was aiming for the kid, if that makes you feel better.
我只是想要那个家伙, 如果那样,你会好受些
Well, you missed!
可是,你没能得逞
That kid is gonna get you killed.
那个家伙会害死你
He worth that?
他值吗?
Well, l got all day.
噢,我的一天
How about you, you got all day?
再看看你的一天
-Jack, you still there? -Yeah.
-Jack,你在吗? -是的
Dtill here.
还在这儿
Well, this is awkward.
这有多愚蠢
When l started this day...
今天,从开始时...
...l never figured on trading 9 mils with my friend.
...我从没想过会追踪 我的朋友跑9英里的路程
l think we stopped being friends right around 8:25, in that bar.
我想我们已经不是朋友了, 就在8:25,那个酒吧里
No.
不
No, that's not gonna erase 20 years together.
不,那些抹不去 我们20年的情谊
We're still friends.
我们还是朋友
Look...
看...
...a lot l'd take back, but l can't.
...我不应当做那些,但是我也没办法
Well, so you move forward. Next day, next case.
你继续 明天,下个案子
-Lines were crossed. -What lines?
-已经过界了 -什么界?
-You hear me? Lines were crossed, Frank. -What lines? There are no lines!
-你听见我说了吗?你已经过界了,Frank? -什么界?没有什么界
There's getting it done and not getting it done, period!
把一切做个了断吧 就在这儿
You put the bad guys away no matter what it takes.
你准备把那个坏家伙带走, 而不管结果怎样
Now, you're gonna ruin the lives...
现在,你会害死许多人...
...of six cops.
...六个警察
Good cops.
好警察
Good men.
好人
Are you ready to sacrifice their lives for that kid?
你打算为了那个坏小子， 牺牲他们的性命?
Hey, Frank.
嗨,Frank
-Frank. -Yeah?
-Frank -嗯?
This is not about me ruining anybody's life.
不是我在毁坏别人的生活
Okay? This is about you.
知道吗?是你
You hear me?
你能听见我说话吗?
Yeah.
是的
You look at that kid's jacket?
你看到那个家伙的夹克了吗?
l did.
我看到了
-Armed robbery, assault, beats old women-- -l never had no armed robbery!
-持枪抢劫,袭击、殴打老妇人... -我从来没有持枪抢劫过
Beats old women over the heads, steals their Docial Decurity checks.
打老妇人的头, 偷窃社会保险金
-One time, l used-- -Shutup. Shutup.
-一次,就那么... -闭嘴,闭嘴
Oh, no, don't tell him to shut up.
不,不,不要让他闭嘴
No, Jack, listen to him. No, that kid, he's sharp.
不,Jack,听他说 不,那个小子,他很聪明
Yeah, he's playing you.
是的,他在耍你
He's sharper than you are.
他比你聪明得多
He's telling you stories, right?
他已经给你讲过他的故事了吧?
He wants to be a good citizen.
他想做个好市民
Go to church.
去教堂
Buy his mother a house.
给他妈妈买个房子
But he has spent more than half his life in prison.
但是他一半的时间都是呆在监狱里
Two hours ago, he was sitting in a cell for weapons possession.
2小时前,他还在牢里, 是因为携带武器
-He's always gonna do what he has done. -l wasn't....
-他总是想去做那些坏事 -我没有...
He is a career criminal. That's who you're protecting.
他是个职业罪犯， 你一直在保护的那个人
-You all right? -Yeah. Frank's got him on the other side.
-你还好吗? -是的,Frank在那边截住了他
He's got my gun too.
他还拿了我的枪
Now, if you can't see how wrong this is...
现在,如果你看不到， 多么愚蠢这是...
...l promise you l will speak from my heart...
...我向你发誓, 我是发自肺腑地...
...when l give the eulogy at your funeral.
...当我在你的葬礼上念悼词时
Do...
所以...
...do you believe the kid?
...你还相信那个家伙吗?
Or do you believe your ex-partner?
还是相信你以前的搭档?
Frank, we're right on the other side of the door.
我们是对的， 在门的那一边
Because...
因为...
...if you believe the kid...
...如果你信任那个小子...
...you got a choice to make.
...你就只有一个选择
Do you go through your ex-partner?
你在想你昔日搭档的话吗?
Or do you choose door number two...
或者你在选择第二条路...
...and go back to where you came, with your gimpy leg and your shot-up hand?
...回到你原来的立场, 还有你受伤的手和腿?
You're not gonna get very far. And what if your ex-partner is right, Jack?
你还走得不远, 如果你的昔日搭档是对的,Jack?
What if he is right, and you're wasting your whole miserable life?
如果他是对的, 你就是在浪费你可怜的生命
-lt's Frank. -You all right?
-我是Frank -你们还好吧?
Yeah. They're in the elevator. Deal the building.
是的,他们在电梯里, 封锁这幢大楼
Come on, Bobby. Come on, get on that.
快点, 快点,上这儿
Everybody out! Police!
所有人都出来,警察
Move, move! Police!
都给我出来,警察 闪开,闪开,警察
-Frank, where are you? -Bobby, l'm coming up!
-你在哪儿? -Bobby,我正往上来
All right. Come on, come on. Upstairs. Deal the stairwell.
好的,快点,快点 上楼,封锁楼道
-All right. -Find the back stairs. Check the roof.
-好的 -去后楼梯找,检查楼顶
-Come on, Mal! This way. -Got you.
-快点,这边 -明白
-Maldonado, seal it up.
-Maldonado,封锁这里
Hello? Hello? Hello?
你好?
-No, nothing. -No answer. He's not there. Come on.
-不,没有 -没有回答,他不在,快点
l never open door.
我从不开门
Please. Please, help.
求你了,帮帮忙
Come on.
快点
Jack, Jack, Jack. Thank you.
Jack,Jack,Jack 谢谢您
-Thank you. Thank you very much. -Thank you very much.
-谢谢,非常感谢 -非常感谢
-You saw that, right? You heard him, right? -Yeah. He never opens the door.
-你看见了吗?你听见了? -是的,他是从不开门的
Thank you very much, sir. Thank you.
非常感谢您,先生,真是太感谢了
-Thank you. Thank you very much, sir. -Thank you.
-谢谢,非常感谢 -谢谢
-You heard him, right, Jack? -Not now, Eddie.
-你听见了吗,Jack? -没有,Eddie
-Keep your voice down. -He said he never opens the door.
-把声音放低点 -他说他从来都不开门
You know what that mean, right?
你明白那是什么意思吗?
Not right now. There's the signs everywhere.
-不是现在 -天意
-Yeah, ADA MacDonald, please. -May I tell her who's calling?
-是的,请找ADA MacDonald -我可以和她讲话吗?
Yeah, tell her it's the guy that's got her witness.
是的,告诉他,就是这个人 她的证人
You're driving a car during a hurricane.
你在暴风雨中行驶
Like:
就象
A hurricane.
暴风雨
And there's three people at a bus stop.
汽车站上有三个人
-A old woman. -Yeah.
-一个老太太 -是的
A friend, like my friend here.
一个朋友,就象我在这儿的这位朋友
Him. He save your life, your friend.
他救了你的命
lt's Detective Mosley for you.
这是探员Mosley在与你讲话
-Mosley? -Yeah?
-Mosley? -是吗?
Where are you? Where's my witness?
你在哪儿? 我的证人在哪儿?
l'm about seven blocks from you.
我在离你7个街区的地方
But there's about a ton of cops between me and you.
但是,在我们之间, 有无数名警察在拦截
And they all want this kid dead.
他们都想他死
Not to mention that you got a leak in your office.
别在办公室里说出来, 会泄漏出去的
-Domebody's talking to these cops. -Dhit.
-有人会给这些警察通风报信的 -该死
What did you think was gonna happen when you pinched Dhue?
当你审问Shue的时候, 你认为会发生什么?
You thought they'd just lay down and go away quietly?
你认为他们会束手就擒, 然后安静地离开?
We thought if we went to the grand jury, Dhue would fold.
我们以为如果去见大陪审团, Shue就会低头认罪
He bent but didn't break.
他现在已经松动了,但是还没有认罪
We were gonna throw it away until we ran into Edward Bunker last night.
我们本来打算放弃了, 可是昨晚我们见了Edward Bunker
Jury's tenure ends at 1 0. Without that kid, they'll vote no bill and it all goes away.
陪审团的时限就在10点,如果没那个人, 他们就会投反对票,一切都将付之流水
He's an eyewitness. He makes this work.
他是目击证人，他会起作用的
Where are you? l'll send my squad. richard, pen.
你在哪儿?我派我的人过去 Richard,笔
What room?
房间号?
-Do, what, are they coming? -Yeah, they're coming.
-那么,他们会来吗? -是的,他们会的
Good. Because l gotta be somewhere, man. l got something to do.
太好了,因为我可以去那个地方了 我可以做我想做的事了
l gotta be someplace by noon. l gotta go get something.
我可以在中午到达那里, 我可以拿到我想要的东西
lt's real important.
这非常重要
-Oh, shit. -Yeah.
-噢,该死 -是的
Ortiz, l'm coming in the building.
我正走进大楼
Frank?
Frank?
-Touhey and Kaller are taken care of. -Good. Find Bobby. He's on the back stairs.
-Touhey和Kaller在盯着呢 -好的,找到Bobby,他在后楼梯
Eddie, come here, put this on. Here, come on, put that on.
Eddie,过这儿来,穿上这个 这儿,快点,打那个穿上
But it's a big, hot, wool shirt. lt's hot. lt's summer.
但是这衣服太大,太厚,而且是羊毛的 太热了,现在是夏天
-You're dressed like a criminal. -Oh, you want me to--?
-你现在穿的象个囚犯 -噢,你想让我...?
You want me to change my--? l get it. But why can't l put that on?
你想我变个...? 我知道了.但是我不想穿那个
-What about this? -What about that?
-这个怎么样? -那个呢?
-What's wrong with this? lt's just a pattern. -He don't even wear that.
-这个怎么不好?这只是个样子 -他还没穿过呢
Just put the-- Here.
就... 这儿
Never mind. What about this?
没关系,这个,行吗?
ls this all right? Mass-transit blue?
这个怎么样?全部是浅蓝的?
When l was locked up, they had me work in the kitchen.
我被关起来的时候, 他们让我在厨房工作
Do one day a little dude walk up to me and say:
所以,有一天,有个人 向我走过来,说:
''Hey, you think you could bake me a cake?''
"嗨,你认为 你能给我烤个蛋糕吗?"
l said, ''Yeah, l'll bake you a cake.''
我说:"是的,我可以."
l ain't tell him l ain't never baked a cake, you know.
我没告诉他,我其实根本不会烤
But l ain't got shit else to do.
但是我不能说
Do, you know, l read the instructions...
我读了说明书...
...l bake him a cake, you know, for his daughter's birthday.
我给他烤了个蛋糕... 那是为他女儿的生日做的
She'd come up there to visit him.
她跑到那儿看我
You know, it say, ''Happy Birthday, Angel,'' right?
她说:"生日快乐,天使." 知道吗?
He go crazy. He can't get enough, you know.
他非常激动,非常满意
He said, ''Eddie, you done hooked me up. Man, you the man.''
他说:"Eddie,你的蛋糕太棒了, 你,就是你."
And l started doing that. lt was good. l had a skill.
我就开始做蛋糕了, 很棒,我有了生存技能
People look at me different. They would start--
人们开始对我另眼相待了, 他们开始...
-You missed a button. -Did l?
-你扣错了一个扣 -是吗?
Your buttons are all crooked.
你的纽扣全扣错了
-Come on. Come on, man. -All right.
-快点,快点 -好的
Nugent.
Nugent
You're a prince.
你真棒
-The word is 5E, boys, 5E. -Got it.
-5E.是5E -知道了
Then l start doing my research, doing my due diligence.
以后,我就开始研究做蛋糕, 尽我最大的努力
l found out, you know, it's good money in birthday cakes for kids, you know.
我学会了很好的生财之道, 给小孩子们做生日蛋糕
That type of thing, like Tweety Bird or Bugs Bunny or something like that.
那一类的东西,就象 小鸟、小兔子或者这一类的东西
Or Yu-Gi-Oh!. You ever heard of Yu-Gi-Oh!?
或者Yu-Gi-Oh 你听说过Yu-Gi-Oh吗?
-Yu-Gi-Oh!. -Yu-Gi-Oh!. Kids love that, man.
-Yu-Gi-Oh -Yu-Gi-Oh!小孩子们喜欢那个
You don't know Yu-Gi-Oh!? You gotta get out more. Yu-Gi-Oh! hot.
你不知道Yu-Gi-Oh? 你应该多到外面转转,Yu-Gi-Oh!很时髦的
Know what l'm saying?
明白我说的吗?
l'm gonna make money, Jack. Open up my bakery.
我就要赚钱了,Jack 开我的蛋糕店
You gonna eat your words about me, Jack. How do l look? Do l look all right?
你就要吃到我的祝福蛋糕了,Jack 我看上去怎么样?我看上去是不是很好?
-All right. -Freeze! Police!
-好的 -别动!警察
-Police! Police! -Shutup!
-警察!警察 -闭嘴
-Oh, my God!
-噢,我的上帝啊 -住口
Frank, they gave us the wrong apartment.
他们给了我们一个错误的房间号码
Put it down.
放下
Can't get lucky all the time.
不能总是那么幸运
You can be smart every day, though.
你可以每天都这么聪明嘛
-All right, give me the gun. -Hold on.
-好的,给我枪 -抓紧
What are you doing?
你要干什么?
This place is crawling with cops, Eddie.
这里四处都是警察,Eddie
Hey, look at me.
嗨,看着我
Eddie, what are you doing?
Eddie,你要干什么?
How does it feel?
感觉怎么样?
You're a baker, right?
你是个面包师,不是吗?
Eddie, listen to him.
Eddie,听他的
Pull that trigger, you go to jail for life.
扣动扳机,你就会终生呆在牢房里
Frank, we're on our way down.
Frank,我们在往下走
Frank, do you read me?
Frank,你听见了吗?
-You can't stop me, you understand? -Time to go.
-你不能阻止我,你明白吗? -快没时间了
-You can't stop me.
-时间就快到了 -你阻止不了我
You gave him a loaded weapon?
你给了他一把上满膛的枪?
-Frank. -Bobby, get these things off me.
-Frank. -Bobby,帮我打开
-Did he take your gun? -They went south. Get out of here.
-他拿走了你的枪? -他们向南跑了,离开这儿
Ortiz! Ortiz, give me a piece. Give me a piece! Get over here.
Ortiz! Ortiz,给我把枪 给我把枪,离开这儿
Make a hole, make a hole. Come on, make a hole.
让开,让开 快点,闪开
Dpeak to me. Come on, somebody, speak to me.
说话,快点, 来个人,给我讲话
Turn.
转过去
-Excuse me! -Open up!
-麻烦您 -开下门
Keep moving. Go. Go, go, go.
继续向前开,快 快,快
Oh, shit.
噢,该死
On the bus! Let's go.
在公共汽车上,我们走
-Just keep driving. -What are you doing?
-只管开车 -你在做什么?
-l'm a cop. Lock the back door. -He's got a gun!
-我是警察,锁上后门 -他有枪
No stops. Tell them to hang on to something, Eddie!
别停下来 告诉他们抓牢,Eddie
Hang on! Don't worry, this man, he's a police officer.
抓牢点,别担心, 这个人,他是个警察
-Everything is gonna be fine. -Hang on!
-一切都会好的 -抓紧些
Everybody just hang on. Don't worry!
每个人都抓稳点儿,别担心
right, right, right! Go right!
往右,往右
-What are you doing? -Dtop this thing!
-你在做什么? -阻止这事
Get down!
下车
Get away from the bus! Away from the bus!
从公车下来,下车
Dtay down! Dtay down!
爬下,爬下
Heads down!
把头低下
-Where the hell are you? -Construction site at Baxter.
-你到底在哪儿? -Baxter工地
He has hostages.
他有人质
Let me go.
让我走吧
Listen!
听着
Everybody, stand up. They're not gonna shoot you.
每个人,都站起来 他们不会向你们开枪的
Dtand up in front of the windows.
站在窗户前
They won't shoot you. You, stay down. Dtay down.
他们不会开枪 你,蹲下,蹲下
Fill in the blanks. Fill in the spots.
不要留空儿
Dcoot over, scoot over! That's it.
站过去,就这些
-All right, get Gruber down here. -Okay.
-好的,让Gruber到这儿来 -是
Hey!
嗨
All right, seal off that end.
好,堵住那头
-lt's a busload. -Jesus, this shit just gets deeper.
-是一车人 -上帝啊,事情越闹越大了
-Bobby? -Gruber's on his way.
-Bobby? -Gruber在路上
All right. We gotta get our stories straight, all right?
我们得把我们的事解决了,明白?
We're getting our stories straight?
我们得解决我们的事,懂吗?
Yeah, suit up.
全副武装
Thought we could handle this quickly and quietly, commissioner.
我们会很好地解决这事的,长官
A guy shoots a cop, takes a grand-jury witness hostage...
一个家伙枪击了一名警察, 带着一个大陪审团需要的目击证人、人质...
...and we're supposed to make nice?
...我们会把一切处理好...
Commissioner, look, sir, this is-- Watch your back, sir.
长官,看,先生,这是... 看看你身后,先生
This is my fault, all right?
是我的错,您知道吗?
l used to work with Mosley, so l asked the captain to let me handle it.
我过去和Mosley一起工作, 所以我请求上尉让我处理这事
l felt that l could bring him in. l just didn't realize how far gone he was.
我没想到他竟然走这么远, 所以我请求上尉要我来处理这事
-Dtay on Tac 2, boys. -Wait for command, here we go.
-按照tac 2行事 -等命令,到这儿来
That's it, cover them up.
就这些,把它们遮住
Good, okay. Great job. Thank you.
好的,做的很好,谢谢
-Commissioner, sir. Captain. -Hi, Mike.
-长官,上尉 -嗨,Mike
-What do we got? -Cop. Twenty plus, flipped.
-怎么样? -警察,再加上20个,转向了
-Duicidal? -Been to the farm twice the last four years.
-自杀? -是最近四年前,去农场那次的两倍
-Twice? -Twice. Nothing like this, though.
-两倍? -两倍,尽管也不象这样
-What do you know, detective? -Like the captain said, he flipped.
-你呢,探员? -就象上尉所说,他转向了
After he nailed Dhue, he started spouting crap about making headlines.
他打了Shue以后,开始试运气了
There's no way that you're getting this guy out.
现在没办法把这个家伙弄出来
Please fall back behind the barricades. On the sidewalk.
都退到路障的后面,人行道上去
Dmart cop.
聪明
Okay. You're all gonna be okay. We're gonna get you out of here.
会好的,你们都会好的, 我们会让你们离开这儿的
-Please, just move to the back of the bus. -Jack?
-请都移到公共汽车的后部 -Jack?
Just move to the back of the bus, please, right now.
只是移到公共汽车后部 拜托,马上
lt's okay. You're gonna get off the bus. l am a police officer.
很好,你们会下车的 我是个警察
Jack, it's Mike Sheehan from HNT.
Jack,我是HNT的Mike Sheehan
We worked that barricade deal on the concourse a few years ago.
几年前,我们一起处理过路障的那起群体事件
l'm gonna put this thing down, okay?
我把这东西放下,好吗?
-l'm sorry. -Jack!
-我很抱歉 -Jack
l'm sorry that l got you in this situation.
很抱歉,让你处于这种境地
You know the drill, no weapons.
你知道我们所受的训练,我没带武器
Listen, you're on the job.
听着,你现在是在车里
-Just keep your head down. -You know the deal.
-把头低下 -你很明白
l'm just gonna step in here, nice and easy...
我只是想在这儿站一下, 很好,很轻松...
...and hand you this phone so we can talk, okay?
...把这个电话给你... 那样我们可以谈谈,行吗?
Make sure we got no injuries in there. Jack, just open the door, okay?
保证不会伤害任何人 Jack,开门,行吗?
-l need to-- -Just throw it, Mike!
-我需要... -扔进来,Mike
-Okay, you got it. -Throw it!
-好的,你拿到了 -扔
Here you go. Jack--
给你,Jack...
Jack, can you hear me?
Jack,能听见我说话吗?
How many people you got in there, Jack?
车里面有多少人,Jack?
Count how many people are here.
数一下这里有多少人
Everybody put your hands up, please.
每个人都把手举起来,拜托
N. Y.P.D., we got a situation here. We need you people back on the sidewalk.
N.Y.P.D,我们在这里 我们需要你把人都送到人行道上
-Stay behind the barricade. -Twenty-six, 28. Okay, thank you.
-呆在路障后面 -26,28,好的,谢谢
That's everybody? Please, don't cry, don't cry.
是所有的人吗? 拜托,别哭,别哭
Everything's gonna be all right, just relax. Dtay calm, okay? Thank you.
一切都会好的,放松 镇静些,好吗?谢谢
-What is it? -Thirty-one. Thirty-one.
-多少? -31
Okay, we have about 40 people on the bus.
我们有40个人在公共汽车上
Okay, that's good.
好,很好
You know, it's important that we're clear with each other, Jack.
你知道,相互了解双方的情况, 这很重要,Jack
ESU and HNT are in place.
ESU和HNT都在这里
The block is sealed, Jack. lt's a frozen zone.
整个街区都被封锁了,Jack 这里已经戒严了
So let's work this out so everybody can go home, all right?
所以,让我们来解决一下问题, 每个人都回家,好吗?
That's all we wanna do. Just end it, nice and easy.
我们想这样,圆满收场
Jack?
Jack?
Jack? This is as far as you go, buddy.
Jack?你只能这么做
Keep talk--
谈谈吧...
-ls everybody okay? -Yeah.
-每个人都好吗? -是的
-Hi, how are you? -Good.
-嗨,你怎么样? -很好
How are you?
你呢?
My name's Eddie. Hi, how you doing? Everybody's okay?
我叫Eddie.嗨,大家好 每个人都好吗?
What's your name?
你叫什么名字?
-Christina.
-Christina
That's a pretty name. How old are you, Christina?
多好听的名字 你多大了,Christina?
-Deven. -Deven years old.
-7岁 -7岁了
And my strawberry recipe-- l know l got one. Let me see.
这是我的草莓食谱... 我知道我有一个,让我瞧瞧
Where's my strawberry recipe? Let's see.
我的草莓食谱?我们来看看
Angel-food-cake recipe right here.
天使食品蛋糕,就在这儿
Here we go, strawberry fan.
这儿,扇形草莓
Dee right here on the top?
看这儿上头
l can put a fan on the top.
我在上面画了个扇形
You know, like a Chinese fan?
你知道吗?就象是中国的扇子
l could do that.
我能做
When's your birthday?
你的生日是哪天?
-Deptember 22nd. -Oh, so that's soon.
-9月22号 -哦,那快到了
Gonna be 8 years old, huh? That's gonna be a good day for you.
要8岁了,那将是你非常幸福的一天
When's your birthday?
你是什么时候生日?
Today, actually.
今天,事实上
-Yeah. -Happy birthday to you.
-是的 -祝你生日快乐
And, yeah, every day is somebody's birthday, you know.
噢,是的,每一天都是某个人的生日
That's gonna be the motto for my shop:
那是我蛋糕店的座右铭
''Every day's a birthday,'' you know.
"每一天都是生日."
l didn't know my birthday was gonna turn out like this, but....
我不知道我的生日会变成这样,但是...
Yeah, l'm glad to be, you know, here, alive, you know.
是的,我喜欢这样 这里,活着
-right here, Jack. -Yeah, Sheehan.
-我在这儿,Jack -是的,Sheehan
Commissioner, sir.
长官大人
-Sheehan? -right here.
-sheehan? -我在这儿
All right. This is what I want.
还好,我希望这样
l want you to get me Assistant District Attorney MacDonald...
我想让你给我找ADA MacDonald
...a court stenographer and somebody from TV.
...法庭速记员,还有电视台的人
Somebody that I would recognize.
还我认识的人
I want them to come on the bus and record sworn testimony.
我想让他们上车, 记录一下发过誓的证词
When l get what l want, l'll let everybody out. Dafely.
等我拿到我想要的, 我就让所有的人安全离开
-That's a tall order. lt'll take some time-- -Just do it. l'm not in the mood, okay?
-这要求太苛刻,要花上一段时间 -就这么做吧,我现在情绪不大稳定,行吗?
Get these people here in 1 5 minutes...
15分钟内,让这些人来这儿...
...or I'm gonna shoot these passengers one at a time...
...不然的话,我会开枪... 一次一个乘客...
-...and throw them out the door. -Jack, be cool, okay?
-...然后,将他们扔出车外 -冷静点,行吗?
Let's not do anything rash. This thing can end without bloodshed.
别冲动,这件事会解决的, 而且不会有流血
-Okay? We can work this-- -Fifteen minutes.
-行吗?我们这就去做... -15分钟
Jack? Jack?
Jack?Jack?
He's gone.
他挂了
All right, everybody on your feet.
好吧,所有人都站起来
-Jack, what are you doing? -Gotta get these people off this bus.
-Jack,你要做什么? -让这些人下车
But you just made your call. You called the DA. They said they'd come.
可是你刚刚打了电话 你叫了DA,他们说他们会来
-Everybody's coming. -Nobody's coming, okay?
-所有人都会来的 -没有人会来,懂吗?
What do you mean, nobody's coming?
你什么意思,没人会来?
They're gonna breach this bus in less than five minutes.
他们会5分钟之内冲进这辆车
-They're gonna kill me, kill you-- -Jack, what about testifying?
-他们会杀了我,也会杀了你... -Jack,那证词?
We're right here. We can go. We can end this.
我们就在这儿,我们得走, 我们得结束这一切
-We can testify. -Nobody's testifying.
-我们可以作证 -没有人作证
lt's all over, Eddie.
一切都结束了,Eddie
We lose, kid.
我们输了
-Hey, ray. -Frank.
-嗨,Ray -Frank
You...?
你...?
You guys going in?
你的人都加入了吗?
The commissioner hasn't given us the green light yet.
行政长官还没有给我们命令
Well, l don't need to remind you that he shot two of us.
我不需要提醒你,他打伤了我们两个人
Enough said.
够了
We got maybe 40 civilians on that bus. Get them out.
我们大概有40个市民在那辆车上, 把他们弄出来
l don't want anybody hurt, including our guys.
我不想任何人受伤,包括我们的人在内
Nobody's gonna get hurt, commissioner. These guys know what to do.
没有人会受伤的,长官 这些人知道该怎么做
-We have movement. -Let's move in.
-我们可以行动了 -行动
-Hold your fire. Repeat, hold your fire. -Move in to the bus. Let's go.
-别开枪,重复,别开枪 -移到车那边去,快点
Hey. What--?
嗨,什么...?
Bob.
Bob
When you get outside--
当你出去的时候...
-Happy birthday. -Thank you.
-生日快乐 -谢谢
They'll take you to a holding area. lt'll be hectic.
他们会带你去一个地方,那儿很热
-But everybody's out there-- -Listen to me, listen to me.
-但是所有人都走了... -听我说,听我说
Once you get outside that perimeter, you just get lost.
一旦你离开那儿,你就马上消失
-What if they--? -Keep moving. You just keep moving.
-如果他们...? -继续走,你就继续走
Come here. You look great.
现在,你看上去不错
Hey, gray suit.
嗨,灰西装
All right? Hands in the air, folks. Don't look back.
好的,大家把手举起来, 别回头
Hands in the air, you'll be all right. You'll be all right.
举着手,你会很安全的 你们会很安全的
Next. Dorry.
下一个,抱歉
Come on, come on, let's go!
快点,快点,
-What is he doing? -How should l know?
-他在做什么? -我怎么会知道?
-l'll let you know when l know. -Don't you--
-我一清楚怎么回事就告诉你 -你不是...?
l'll let you know when l know. Out of my face!
我一旦知道了,会让你知道的, 离开我
Kaller, give me a hand with them!
Kaller,给我个人手
Bobby? right there. right here.
Bobby?这儿,这儿
-That's him. That's him. -Hey, man!
-是他,是他 -嗨,你
-lt's not him. -Let him go.
-不是他 -让他走
-The dude, he changed. lt's not me. -What?
-他换了装,不是我 -什么?
-He's in a suit, a gray suit. -Duit, gray suit.
-他穿了身西装,灰色的 -西装,灰色的西装
-We count 31 . -That leaves eight people on the bus.
-我们数了,一共31 -车上还有9个
No, l was the last one off the bus.
不,我是最后一个下车的
The only person left on that bus is the guy with the gun.
车上只剩下那个拿枪的人
-Then go, do it! -Let's go, let's go.
-那么快走 -我们走
-Get your people out there. Let's go. -Come on, let's go.
-把你的人带走,我们走 -快点,快点
Mosley is still on the bus. That kid is here somewhere. We checked--
Mosley 还在车上，那家伙一定 在这儿的某个角落,我们得查...
Bobby, l don't care what you checked.
Bobby,我不管你怎么查
Check it again, now. Go. You guys, that way.
再检查一遍,快去 你们,那边
This is Detective Jack Mosley. Dhield number 227.
我是探员Jack Mosley 徽号227
l guess this will be my last will and testament.
我想这将是我的遗嘱和最后誓词
Don't shoot!
别开枪
-Who is that? -Hold your fire!
-那是谁? -别开枪
-Is it that wit from the 32?
-是那个第32个,目击证人
Get on your goddamn radio. Find out who that is.
打开你那该死的对讲机, 弄清楚那是谁
Guns down, hold your fire!
放下枪,别开枪
Don't shoot!
别开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
别开枪,别开枪
-Do not move! Dtep away from the bus! -Don't shoot, hold your fire!
-别动,离开那辆车 -别开枪,别开枪
-Do not shoot! -Get away from the bus!
-别开枪 -离开那车
Hold your fire.
别开枪
Jack. Jack, it's me. Jack Mosley!
Jack,Jack,是我 Jack Mosley
lt's me, Eddie, Jack.
是我Eddie,Jack
Chuck Berry.
Chuck Berry
Chuck Berry, he got locked up for armed robbery.
Chuck Berry,他因为持枪抢劫被关起来
He changed. He changed.
他变了,他变了
Barry White, he stole 300 tires.
Barry White,他偷了300辆车
Can you picture big Barry White stealing 300 tires? He changed.
你能想象出Barry White偷了300辆车? 他变了
You said-- You said people don't change.
你说...你说人不会变
-People change. -Eddie.
-人会变 -Eddie
-What? -You're killing me.
-什么? -你要害死我
Team three, breach the bus. repeat, team three, breach the bus.
第三小队,突破那辆车 重复,第三小队,突破那辆车
Get out of the way!
闪开
Head down! Cover your ears and your eyes!
低头 捂住耳朵,挡上眼睛
-Hold fire. -Go, go!
-别开枪 -快,快
This is a nightmare.
这真是场恶梦
Hold fire!
别开枪
-Let's go! Move, move, move! -Dtay down!
-快走,快走 -停下来
-Move up! Move up! -Come here.
-往前,往前 -到这儿来
Team two, status?
2队,情况怎么样?
Go ahead! Take it! Go!
往前,放那儿
The bus is empty.
车里面是空的
They went through the bus doors!
他们从车门那儿溜走了
They're in the goddamn building! Deal it off!
他们进了那幢大楼了, 封锁那里
-All clear. The bus is empty. -They've entered the building.
-车上是空的 -他们已经进了大楼
Deal the building, start a search.
封锁大楼,开始搜查
remember, heads up. He just shot two cops. Be careful.
记住,抬头 他刚枪击了两个警察,小心点
Jack, l gotta tell you something.
Jack,我想跟你说个事
Hey, man. Jack, listen to me, man.
嗨,Jack,听我说
Jack, l wanna tell you something.
Jack,我想跟你说件事
Hold on, hold on, wait. l gotta tell you something. lt's important.
坚持一下,等等 我想告诉你一件事,很重要
Dhit. Get up, go.
该死,站起来,走
Oh, shit.
噢,真该死
Hey, sir. l'm a cop, all right? l'm on the job.
嗨,先生,我是警察, 我在执行公务
Look, l need that phone for a minute.
我需要借您的电话用一下
Look what you did to my suit, man.
看看你把我的西装弄的
l told you you was gonna get me shot.
我跟你说过,你会让我中枪的
lt's me. l need your help.
是我,我需要你帮助
All this started because my friend Maurice came by my house.
所有这一切都是因为 我的朋友Maurice,到我这儿来
Two days ago,
2天前,Maurice来到我家
He all excited.
他很兴奋
He got a shoebox.
他得到一个鞋盒子
He had a gun.
他拿到了一把枪
He talking about, ''Hold this for me for a little while.''
他说到:"我借用一会儿."
l'm like, ''l'm on parole.'' He like, ''Me too.''
我就象是,"是假释出狱的." 他也是
Next day, somebody shot him.
第二天,他被杀了
Thirty-two thousand dollars in that shoebox.
那个鞋盒子里面有3万2千美元
-That's a sign, huh? -Yeah.
-那是天意 -是的
lt's a very big sign.
很大的暗示
Easy, easy, easy.
放松些
You know how much it gonna take me to open the bakery?
你知道我需要有多少钱 来开一个蛋糕店吗?
Thirty-one thousand dollars.
3万1千美元
Jack, l got so nervous l ran out the house.
Jack,我很紧张, 我跑了出去
l went to Port Authority and l put the money in a locker.
我去了港务局,把钱锁了起来
l get back to my house...
我回到我的房间...
...my parole officer's there...
...我的假释官站在那儿...
...in my house.
...在我的房间里
He got Maurice's gun in his hand.
他手里拿着Maurice的那把枪
He looking at me like, ''That's it, Eddie.''
他看着我,意思是说:"那就是,Eddie."
And he's talking about 1 5 years, man.
他说要15年
l got so sick.
我吓坏了
Then the DA came to my cell...
然后DA来到我的牢房...
...and he showed me the picture of that cop.
...他给我看了...... 那个警察的照片
Then l met you.
然后我就遇到了你
Jack, they clean them lockers out every 24 hours.
他们每隔24小时就会清理一下那些柜子
l had a little schedule going, man.
我还有不多的时间了
Court at 1 0:00...
法院是10点...
...Port Authority at 1 2.
...港务局是12点
Hey. Hey, look at me. Wake up.
嗨,看着我,醒醒
You ain't gonna die on me, are you?
别死在我面前
l don't know, l never died before.
我不知道,我以前还没死过呢
lt's not gonna happen today.
不是在今天
Hey. Thank you for coming.
嗨!谢谢你能过来
-What's going on? -Look. Dhot here. l think it went in and out.
-发生了什么? -看,枪伤在这儿,我想是从这儿进出的
Yeah, let's get him in.
嗯,把他抬到车里
l know you.
我认识你
-Come on. -l was at your house.
-快点 -在你的房间里
-You were at my apartment? -Had to get my gun.
-你到过我的房间? -得去拿我的枪
Bigmouth.
大嘴
lt was very nice, very clean.
很好,很干净
The police grilled me for an hour at the hospital.
警察在医院里盘问了我一个小时
What'd you say to them?
你怎么对他们说的?
That you're a self-medicating, depressed individual.
你在自已治疗,很抑郁
And you don't care about anything or anyone.
你不关心别人或别的什么事
Oh, she's honest, straightforward. That's sexy. l like that.
噢,她很诚实,很直率, 很性感,我喜欢
What'd you do this time, Jack?
你这段时间在做什么,Jack?
He saved my life a couple times.
他救了我好几次
Hey, he's a good dude. You gotta give him another chance.
他是个好人,你应当再给他一个机会
l don't know what he did, but you gotta give him another chance.
-我不明白他在说什么 -但是,你应当再给他个机会
He gotta have somebody to talk to.
他需要有个人和他聊聊
l'm not gonna be around.
我要不在他身边了
-Eddie, this is my sister, Diane. -What?
-Eddie,她是我妹妹,Diane -什么?
She's your sister?
她是你妹妹?
Oh, man.
噢!你这人
l just started having a little hope for you. Your family don't even like you.
我本来还对你抱有希望的, 你们家人甚至也不喜欢你
l got a sister too.
我也有个妹妹
But she live in Deattle.
她住在西雅图
l was supposed to go out there and start my bakery.
我想在那儿附近开个蛋糕店
l was supposed to go out there today to see her.
我本该到那儿看她的
Dee her on the bus.
在公共汽车上
l can stop the bleeding...
我可以止住血...
...but he's gotta get stitched up, get to a hospital.
...但是,他需要到医院去缝合一下...
We gotta be at the courthouse in less than 20.
我们得在20分钟内到达法院
You're gonna have to do it.
你们得这么做
You're gonna be fine, Eddie. lt's not as bad as it looks.
你会好的,Eddie,看起来没那么糟
What happened to your hand?
你的手怎么了?
l gotta ask you one more favor.
我想你再帮我个忙
Just a little favor.
一个小忙
Hey, is today really your birthday?
嗨,今天真的是你的生日吗?
No.
不
No, l just said that because the little girl, she was so scared.
不,我刚才那么说是因为 那个小女孩,她很害怕
She was cute, man.
她很可爱
When's your birthday?
你的生日是什么时候?
-l don't know. -What do you mean, you don't know?
-我不知道 -什么意思,你不知道?
No, for real, l don't know.
不,是真的,我不知道
l'm not-- l came up in foster care. Had a lot of birthdays.
我不是...我是在看护所长大的, 有许多个生日
But didn't you say--? You got a sister, right? That you're going to see?
但是你说...?你有个妹妹? 你还要去看她?
Yeah, l just found out about her a couple months ago.
是的,我是在几个月前找到她的
-Never met your sister? -No.
-从来没见过她? -没有
That's why l'm going out to Deattle to meet her.
那就是我为什么要到西雅图去看她
l'm looking forward.
我期待着
Maybe she turns out to look like Angelina Jolie.
也许她看起来象Angelina Jolie
Dhit, if she do, l hope she ain't my sister.
该死,如果她是那样, 我希望她不是我妹妹
Hey, man, what you want on your cake, man?
嗨,你想在蛋糕表面写些什么?
You never told me. l gotta send you one, man.
你还没告诉我,我想送你一个
-l don't want no cake, Eddie. -Damn it, Jack, come on, man--
-我不想要蛋糕,Eddie -该死,Jack,快点...
l can't think of anything that has happened in my life...
我不再想我生活中所发生的...
-...that l would want written on a cake. -Nothing?
-...我想写在蛋糕上的.... -没有?
l'm not a good guy, Eddie.
我不是个好人,Eddie
l'm not a good guy.
我不是个好人
Yeah, me neither.
噢,我也不是
-Diane. -Frank.
-Diane. -Frank.
Give me the keys.
给我钥匙
-Dtay in the car. -Little out of your sector, aren't you?
-呆在车里 -超出你的职业范围了,不是吗?
Daving lives knows no bounds.
挽救生命是没有底线的
-You should know that, Frank. -You look good.
-你应该知道,Frank -你看上去不错
You look a little desperate. Doesn't suit you.
你看上去有点绝望,这可不象你
Open the door.
打开门
Open the door. Open the door.
开门,打开门
Sorry, Jack, this is as close as l can get you.
抱歉,Jack,我只能送你到这儿了
Like l said, you're looking good.
就象我说的,你看上去不错
Thanks, kid.
谢谢
All right, come on, let's go.
好的,快点,我们走
No, hey, hold on. Hold on a minute.
不,嗨,等等,再等一下
Why is that? Hold on for what?
为什么?等什么?
This is as far as you go too.
这一次尽量走得越远越好
-Come on, man. l don't-- -Listen to me, Eddie.
-快点,我不能... -听我说,Eddie
-What? -Listen.
-什么? -听着
Those guys you were gonna testify against...
你将要做证告发的人当中...
-...those cops? -Yeah?
-...那些警察? -是吗?
l was one of them.
我是其中一个
You were gonna testify against me too.
你要作证控告的人当中,也包括我
l did what they did.
我也做了跟他们同样的事
We did some bad things.
我们做了一些坏事
l did another bad thing when l used you.
我利用你做另一件坏事
l was gonna let you do what l should have done.
我想让你做我本该做的事
What l should have had the courage to do six years ago.
六年前,我就应当有这种勇气
l'm sorry.
对不起
You know, if you didn't come to get me today...
你知道,如果今天你没带上我...
...l'd be dead right now.
...我现在已经死了
-right. -So....
-现在 -所以...
l was supposed to meet you.
我应当遇到你
That was the sign.
那是天意
You saved my life, kid.
你拯救了我
Take care of yourself, kid.
照顾好自己
Thank you.
谢谢你
Make cakes, Eddie the baker.
烤蛋糕,Eddie, 做个面包师
Oh, yeah. You give the car keys to your best friend.
噢,是的,你把你的车钥匙 给了你最好的朋友
You let him take the old lady to the hospital.
你让他送那个老女人去了医院
You stay at the bus stop with the girl because she's the girl of your dreams, right?
你陪那个女孩留在公共汽车站上, 因为她是你的梦中情人,对吗?
So everything's gonna be okay.
所以,一切都会好的
-right? -Yeah.
-对吗? -是的
Have fun in Deattle. Day hi to your sister.
在西雅图玩好,向你妹妹问好
Yeah.
好的
Get him to the Port Authority. Make sure he gets on that bus.
把他送到港务局 确保他上了那辆公共汽车
-Carl, thanks. -No problem.
-Carl,谢谢 -没问题
All right.
好的
Hell of a morning, huh?
怎样的一个早上,啊?
Where's the wit?
那个证人呢?
You're looking at him.
你们在看着他
l let the kid go, Frank.
我让他走了,Frank
-You're not gonna get to him now. -Bullshit.
-你不会再找到他了 -废话
Wouldn't do that.
别那样
So...
还有...
...what do you think you're gonna tell them?
...你想对他们说什么?
Are you gonna tell them everything?
你想告诉他们所有的一切?
Are you gonna tell them about you too?
你还想告诉他们,这其中也包括你?
You think that's gonna make you feel better?
你认为那样做,你会好过点儿?
Nothing's gonna make me feel better.
没有什么会使我好过些
Then why?
那为什么?
Look, Jack, you and me...
看,Jack,你,还我...
...we did our business in a certain way.
...我们都做了那事...
You never complained when we cleared the tough cases.
当我们把那个棘手的案子了结时, 你并没有说什么
lt didn't bother you doing any of that until....
你根本没有困惑,直到...
Listen to me, all right? You listen.
听我说,好吗?听我说
Okay, Jack? really listen.
好吧,Jack?仔细听着
Whatever you think that you are gonna do up there...
不论你想上去做什么...
...it is never gonna happen.
...一切都不会发生...
You are not gonna make it.
你办不到
ls that what you're thinking, Frank?
这就是你的想法,Frank?
You're gonna shoot me down here? Nobody knows?
你想在这儿杀了我? 没有人会知道?
Like the Ling family, huh?
就象Ling一家人,是不是?
Like they never knew.
没人知道
He was a stupid old man who wouldn't keep his mouth shut.
他是个蠢老头,谁都想封住他的嘴
All right, so l stuck a gun in some guy's mouth.
所以,我把枪放进他的嘴里
-He had a heart attack, he died. So what? -So what?
-他心脏病发作,死了,还有什么? -还有什么?
Look, if it hadn't happened the way that it did, if he hadn't died...
看,如果不发生那事,如果他没死...
...you would've been patting me on the back, saying, ''Good job.''
...你就会拍着我的后背, 说:"干得好!"
Collateral damage, it is a fact of life in this business.
大家都受到了伤害,这就是这件事情的真相
He took his last breaths while you were wiping the fingerprints off the room.
当你擦拭屋里的指纹时,他咽下了最后一口气
-He was gonna take down our case. -He was an innocent man.
-他想接下我们的案子 -他是无辜的
-He was somebody's husband.
-他是想接管我们的案子 -他有妻子
-He was gonna take down our case. -He was somebody's father.
-他想接管我们的案子 -他还有孩子
He was gonna take down our case! What were we supposed to do?
-他是要接管我们的案子 -我们能做什么?
-He wanted to tell the truth. -Fuck the truth!
-他只想说出真相 -去他妈的真相
right.
好吧
l'm not gonna need this anymore.
我不再需要它了
Bobby? He's on his way up.
Bobby? 他上去了
Take him out.
把他弄出来
Mosley's in the building! Get the ADA. Freeze!
Mosley在大楼里 快通知ADA,别动
-Hands in the air! -Don't shoot.
-举起手来 -别开枪
-Don't move! Down on your knees. -l'm not armed.
-别动,蹲下 -我身上没带枪
-Down on your knees! Now! -Don't shoot, l'm not armed.
-蹲下,现在 -别开枪,我身上没带枪
Lower your weapon. Just call ADA MacDonald, please, on the radio.
放下枪,去找ADA的MacDonald 拜托,用对讲机
-Hands up. -Get ADA MacDonald here right now!
-举起手来 -请ADA MacDonald赶快到这儿来
-Don't shoot. Don't shoot me. -Get your hands up!
-别开枪,千万别开枪 -把手举起来
Just get ADA MacDonald for me.
帮我把ADA MacDonald找来
-Jack, come on! -l won't argue with you. Get down.
-Jack,快点 -我不是在和你辩论,蹲下
Mosley! Mosley!
Mosley! Mosley
Hands up!
举起手
Where's my witness? Where's Edward Bunker?
我的证人在哪儿? Edward Bunker在哪儿?
He didn't make it.
他来不了了
l'm gonna take his place.
我将代替他
-Please lower your weapons. -Hold your fire and stand down.
-请放下枪 -别开枪,站在那儿
Back off.
往后退
l have information...
我有证据...
...regarding your ongoing witness-tampering investigation.
...有关你正在调查的贿赂案...
Dates, cases that include extortion...
包括敲诈的日期,案件...
...manslaughter and possible homicide...
...过失杀人,还有可能存在的谋杀...
...involving members of the 1 4th Precinct.
...包括第14巡逻区所有的成员
These charges include Captain Dan Gruber...
指控包括Dan Gruber上尉...
...detectives Jerry Dhue...
...探员Jerry Shue...
...Edward Maldonado...
...Edward Maldonado...
...Bob Torres...
...Bob Torres...
...Jim Mulvey...
...Jim Mulvey...
...myself...
...还有我...
...and Detective Frank Nugent.
...和Frank Nugent探员
What's this about, Mosley? What do you want?
这是什么,Mosley? 你想干什么?
l want Edward Bunker's record expunged.
我想证实Edward Bunker的记录
-Done. What else? -Nothing else.
-好的,还有什么? -没了
You can substantiate all this, Mosley?
你能证实所有的一切,Mosley?
Yeah.
是的
Gun!
枪
Hold your fire. l fired that shot.
别开枪,我击中了那个人
You're gonna shoot me down here? Nobody knows?
你想在这儿杀了我? 没有人会知道?
Like the Ling family, huh?
象对Ling一家人那样?
Like they never knew.
没人会知道
He was a stupid old man who wouldn't keep his mouth shut.
他是个蠢老头,谁都想封住他的嘴
All right, so I stuck a gun in some guy's mouth.
所以,我把枪放进他的嘴里
-He had a heart attack, he died. So what? -So what?
-他心脏病发作,死了,还有什么? -还有什么?
-So how about he was innocent?
-还有他是无辜的,又怎样?
-Innocent? -How about he didn't deserve to die?
-无辜? -他就是不该死,又怎样呢?
Look, if it hadn't happened the way that it did, if he hadn't died...
瞧,如果没发生那事,如果他没死...
...you would've been patting me on the back, saying, ""Good job. ""
...你会拍着我的后背, 说:"干得好!"
Collateral damage, it is a fact of life in this business.
大家都受到了伤害,这就是事实
He took his last breaths while you were wiping the fingerprints off the room.
他在你擦拭房间里的指纹时, 咽下了最后一口气
-He was gonna take down our case. -He was an innocent man.
-他要接管我们的案子 -他是无辜的
-He was somebody's husband.
-他有妻子
-He was gonna take down our case. -He was somebody's father.
-他想接管我们的案子 -他还有孩子
He was gonna take down our case! What were we supposed to do?
他想接管我们的案子, 那么我们该怎么办?
-He wanted to tell the truth. -Fuck the truth!
-他想说出真相 -去他妈的真相
Let's get you to the jury.
我们带你去陪审团
-Thanks a lot. -Thanks.
-非常感谢 -谢谢
Okay.
好的
-Hey, happy birthday. -Happy birthday, Jack.
-嗨!生日快乐 -生日快乐,Jack
Welcome back, Jack.
欢迎回来,Jack
-Are you kidding me? -Two years in the pen is enough.
-你逗我开心? -两年一只笔就足够了
Thanks for that memory. Thank you.
谢谢你还记得那事
-Happy birthday, Jack. -Happy birthday.
-生日快乐,Jack -生日快乐
-Happy birthday. Blow them out. -Welcome home.
-生日快乐,把蜡烛吹灭 -欢迎回家
l hate birthdays, you know that, right?
我讨厌生日,你是知道的
-Sorry, sorry. -Happy birthday.
-抱歉 -生日快乐
This came with it.
还有这个
Dear Jack Mosley:
亲爱的Jack Mosley:
I hope you're doing well and everything worked out like it was supposed to.
希望你一切安好, 所有的一切都象想象中那样
I'm doing great.
我做得很好
Seattle is different, and I like it a lot.
西雅图很不一样,我非常喜欢这里
I'm not sure I ever smelled fresh air before I got here. It's a trip.
在来这里之前,我不敢说我确曾 呼吸到过新鲜的空气,这是一个旅程
Sometimes I can't believe it. It's the best feeling I've had in my life.
有时,我都不敢相信, 这是我生命中所拥有的幸福的时光了
I'm busting my ass, but I'm happy, though.
我胖了,但是很开心
The bakery is now open. Three cheers.
蛋糕店已经开业了 三个祝福
I put my name first because I'm doing all the hard work.
我把我的名字放在前面最前面, 因为我一直在努力地工作
These ovens are hot, man.
这些烤箱很热
Hope you like the cake. What did I tell you?
希望你喜欢这个蛋糕, 我告诉过你什么呢?
-That's Eddie. -If you're ever in town, you got a friend.
-那是Eddie -如果来这儿,你就有个朋友了
Thank you for doing the right thing, Jack Mosley. God bless you.
谢谢你做了件非常正确的事情， 愿上帝保佑你
Keep in touch. Peace.
保持联系,一切平安
-That's great. -Go on, take one more. Look.
-太好了 -继续,再来一个,瞧啊
You know how this guy--? l was talking, take one more.
你知道这个家伙吗? 我在说,再来一个
Happy birthday, Jack.
生日快乐,Jack